RESUME

Zubair bin Abu Hasan

zubairabuhasan@gmail.com | +60177165025 https://3ub41r.github.io/

I have been building software for a living for more than 10 years specifically in the **tertiary education sector**.

I try to write maintainable code, most of the time. I am always excited about solving problems with or without building software.

Most of my time is spent on building and maintaining **web applications** with ASP.NET and PHP (mainly Laravel). I work with MySQL and Microsoft SQL servers. Occasionally I get invited to teach.

Work Experiences

UTMSPACE

2010 - 2015

UTMSPACE is a subsidiary of Universiti Teknologi Malaysia (UTM) responsible for implementing UTM's lifelong learning programs.

I was hired as an **Assistant Executive** to develop an **academic management system** to manage UTMSPACE's Executive Programs. I was then entrusted with the responsibility of managing and maintaining TEAMS, a system built to manage UTMSPACE's **core product**. I was later promoted to the position of **Executive**.

I also built **ICLAIMS** (**Sistem Tuntutan Syarahan Pensyarah**), which automated most of the process for submitting and disbursing claims. Lecturers no longer need to submit claims and payments are automatically disbursed at the end of the semester.

Gates IT Solutions

2015 - 2016

Gates IT Solutions is a software development company with offices in Johor and Kuala Lumpur with clients all over Malaysia.

I worked as a **System Analyst + Programmer** on a **housing management system** for Pejabat Setiausaha Kerajaan Johor. It was built with Java and MySQL. My main

role was to design and manage the database.

UTMSPACE

2016 - current

I was offered the opportunity to rejoin UTMSPACE in 2016. A few of my recent projects:

Sistem Ambilan Mahasiswa (SAM)

SAM started as an initiative with the Admissions Department to build an admission system that would act as a flexible and centralized **top-of-the-funnel tool** as UTMSPACE was diversifying into other products.

I learned a lot about product development and how critical understanding users is in building products.

Sistem Maklumat Pelajar (SMP) v2

I rewrote SMP, an online **academic management system** for PSM (Program Separuh Masa) students. The old codebase was difficult to maintain and changes were hard to deploy. We implemented a **CI/CD pipeline** to automate builds and deployments.

The user interface was revamped to be easier to use and we also added a feature that encouraged students to provide feedback.

• Upgrade UTMSPACE's payment gateway

I upgraded our payment gateway to conform to the changes introduced by FPX. We managed to save RM500,000 in development costs by **reverse-engineering** the existing system (which was outsourced) and rewriting it.

Introduced a CI/CD Environment

I helped set up a **central code repository and build-server**. Since then it has helped us **enhance collaborations** and has made **deployments much simpler** and **less error-prone**.

Teaching and Training

Once in a while, I get invited to teach. Teaching is very fulfilling. A few of my recent gigs:

"Database Programming" trainer for MDEC Super Programmer organized by GATES IT Solutions

I was privileged to teach a class of selected UTHM students on database fundamentals and designs.

Building A Filing System From Scratch With Laravel

A 3-day course covering the basics of conceptualizing requirements using Use Case Diagrams, Flow Charts, and Entity Relationship Diagrams. The designs were then implemented with Laravel.

ASP.NET and SQL Server training

3-day courses on building web applications with ASP.NET MVC and SQL Server.

Education

- BCS, Bachelor in Computer Science (Software Engineering)
 December 2010, Universiti Malaysia Pahang (UMP), CGPA: 3.36
- Diploma in Computer Science (Software Engineering)
 September 2007, Universiti Malaysia Pahang (UMP), CGPA: 3.36

Personal Endeavors

I have built a few software products. The ones that are still operational are

- 1. **OrderSiapSiap** (https://ordersiapsiap.my) A simple WhatsApp ordering form for small food sellers.
- 2. **Mudeer** (https://mudeer.my) A system to manage students and teachers for education centers offering Arabic and Al-Quran classes.